<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Cycling Routes LT</string>

    <!-- Strings that are common for a number of activities & fragments:-->
    <string name="Open_a_map">Map internet link</string>
    <string name="Toast_message_at_opening_a_map">If you would like to view the map in a dedicated maps application, open Task Manager and exit web browser application.\n\nFor navigating back to Cycling Routes LT application you may need to open Cycling Routes LT from Task Manager.</string>

    <!-- Names of the 4 main regions:-->
    <string name="region_East">Eastern region</string>
    <string name="region_South">Southern region</string>
    <string name="region_West">Western region</string>
    <string name="region_North">Northern region</string>

    <!-- Action bar's labels:-->
    <string name="action_bar_region_East">Routes in Eastern region</string> <!-- DELETE IF UNUSED-->
    <string name="action_bar_region_South">Routes in Southern region</string>
    <string name="action_bar_region_West">Routes in Western region</string>
    <string name="action_bar_region_North">Routes in Northern region</string>

    <!-- Routes in East:-->
    <string name="east_r01_name">An Outing to Neris Regional Park</string>
    <string name="east_r01_distance">62 km</string>
    <string name="east_r01_start_end">Vilnius - Rykantai</string>
    <string name="east_r01_difficulty">2</string>
    <string name="east_r01_full_description"><b>The route:</b> Major part of this route will pass throw forests. Hills are numerous, but not challenging, views are abundant and rewarding. In a number of places you can make shortcuts, but it is well worth to do the full route. Take a good map or GPS or else some crossroads will be heads or tails guess. There is a railway stop at the end, thus logistics is really easy.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> A few interesting hiking trails near Dukstos village. Scenic meanders of Neris river. Beautiful forest routes along Neris regional park.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b> You can start in Vilnius centre, but the actual route outside the town is from city district - Pilaite. From Rykantai it is easy to hop on a train going to either Vilnius or Kaunas.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 2.  Around 80\u0025 of the route is gravel, remaining 20\u0025 - paved. Some small sections will surprise you wit cobblestone.</string>

    <string name="east_r02_name">Through Asveja Regional Park</string>
    <string name="east_r02_distance">86 km</string>
    <string name="east_r02_start_end">Pabrade - Vilnius</string>
    <string name="east_r02_difficulty">2</string>
    <string name="east_r02_full_description"><b>The route:</b> The whole journey can be divided into 3 sections. You will enjoy forests and numerous lakes in the first part. Second third will be less scenic, but easier to pedal. Some more beautiful lakes and an interesting open air museum will wait in the last leg.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> Numerous lakes and a delightful route. Europos parkas - a particularly interesting open air museum (bicycle friendly).\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b> Starting point in Pabrade has good train connection with Vilnius. Your finish line will await you back in the capital.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 2.  Around 80\u0025 of the route is paved, remaining 20\u0025 - gravel. Some sections past Nemencine have more heavy traffic.</string>

    <string name="east_r03_name">Southern Hills Near Capital</string>
    <string name="east_r03_distance">95 km</string>
    <string name="east_r03_start_end">Vilnius - Vilnius</string>
    <string name="east_r03_difficulty">2</string>
    <string name="east_r03_full_description"><b>The route:</b> It fascinates how just a dozen kilometers away from the capital life gets much slower and very rural in deed. Start and end locations of this route are rather arbitrary. You can easily modify them depending on how you want to plan your logistics and whether you are not annoyed by city traffic.\n\nMedieval castle, a mosque (a rarity in this region) and an interesting forested heath of Rudninkai forest await. If time and endurance allow you - take a detour deeper into the heath. You will find inland dunes and a rather unusual countryside. There are no good lakes around the route. However, Merkys river is just as refreshing. It will be close near by for quite some time. You can give it a try.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> Medininkai castle. Medininkai uplands. Rudninkai heath. A mosque in Keturiasdesimt Totoriu village.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b> You can start and finish in Vilnius centre. Although probably, it would be a more pleasant option to arrange a car pick-up or drop of at the outskirts of the town. This would let you avoid the traffic.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 2.  Route is mostly paved, a section near Rudninkai heath is rather sandy. Sections near the start and end points have more traffic.</string>

    <string name="east_r04_name">Around an Island - Dieveniskes Park Loop</string>
    <string name="east_r04_distance">52 km</string>
    <string name="east_r04_start_end">Poskonys - Poskonys</string>
    <string name="east_r04_difficulty">1</string>
    <string name="east_r04_full_description"><b>The route:</b> An interesting route through one of the most remote regions of the country. Even though the capital is just some 60 kilometers away, here you get a feeling of being in an island. Almost from every side you are surrounded by a border. Therefore, do not forget your passport.\n\nThe other key reasons not to miss this place is its old traditional villages and countryside, which is different from most of Lithuania. There are numerous villages scattered around between the patches of forest grooves.  A lot of buildings look like they did not change for the last century. However, they are slowly being abandoned and give way to the rule of time.\n\nAs for the surrounding nature - icefields of the last ice age have stopped just at the outskirts of Dieveniskes regional park. Therefore, hills and valleys here are older that elsewhere and you should see the difference in their gently rolling pattern.\n\nThe route can be easily done in a day, but you can spend a night in a few modest campsites. Do not miss Norviliskes castle and fell free to make a turn to smaller roads - this way you will see even more remote localities.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> Remote somewhat abandoned, but pleasant villages. Norviliskes castle. Scenery of Dieveniskes regional park.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b> The route starts and ends at the headquarters of the regional park. You would have to transport your bicycle with a car, as there is not convenient public transport here. An alternative would be to catch a bus to Salcininkai town, that is 20 kilometers away from the start.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 1.  Roughly around 50\u0025 of the route - paved, 50\u0025 - gravel, some sections are with rather irritating potholes.</string>

    <string name="east_r05_name">Ignalina Lake District Loop</string>
    <string name="east_r05_distance">62 km</string>
    <string name="east_r05_start_end">Ignalina - Ignalina</string>
    <string name="east_r05_difficulty">3</string>
    <string name="east_r05_full_description"><b>The route:</b> Perfect combination of rural landscapes, lakes and forests. One of those routes where a rather small distance gives such a big number of sights. Well worth to take a tent and find a camping spot somewhere on your way. This shall not be difficult.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b>  Lakes, forests and, yes - lakes.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Rather frequent railway service to the start / end. Alternatively, you could start at Tauragnai. This would require a bus service to Utena - a not difficult task. The route between Utena and Tauragnai is really scenic.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 3.  Around 60\u0025 of the route is gravel. Remaining 40\u0025 - is shared between pavement and sandy forest roads.</string>

    <string name="east_r06_name">A Slice of Central Aukstaitija</string>
    <string name="east_r06_distance">88 km</string>
    <string name="east_r06_start_end">Pabrade - Anyksciai</string>
    <string name="east_r06_difficulty">2</string>
    <string name="east_r06_full_description"><b>The route:</b> With numerous bends and wide scenery around, this route will not let you get bored. Besides, at almost each hour of travel there will be a lake waiting.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> Numerous lakes and a delightful route. Cozy towns of Moletai and Anyksciai, followed by similarly charming smaller townships of Inturke, Alanta and other. Narrow gauge railway with an interesting museum exposition.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b> The starting point in Pabrade can be easily reached by rail. From Anyksciai it will not be difficult to catch a bus to further major towns - Vilnius, Kaunas, Panevezys. With advance planning you could even continue your travel using narrow gauge railway. Its service, however, is sparse.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 2.  Mostly paved.</string>

    <string name="east_r07_name">How North Becomes South</string>
    <string name="east_r07_distance">80 km</string>
    <string name="east_r07_start_end">Turmantas - Ignalina</string>
    <string name="east_r07_difficulty">3</string>
    <string name="east_r07_full_description"><b>The route:</b> A combination of two opposites - perfectly remote and at the same time easily accessible. The starting 25 or so kilometers will lead you through similarly remote part of Latvia. Rarely used gravel roads, seldom villages, and perfect calmness.\n\nTraveling in the remote north of Lithuania, you will also pass the southernmost point of Latvia. Afterwards, a few road signs like this: "2km to Belarus" - may seem tempting, but unfortunately currently there are no working border crossings here. Thus, you will fully immerse into nature and could even bet whether more than a few dozen of cars shall pass you this countryside.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b>  Southernmost point of Latvia. Tilze village with Druksciai lake. Visaginas town - an interesting example how one should cope with economic crisis. Ignalina lake district.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Easy access by train to both start and end.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 3.  Around 70\u0025 of the route is paved. Remaining 30\u0025 - gravel, mostly at the start.</string>

    <string name="east_r08_name">Small Town Hopping</string>
    <string name="east_r08_distance">116 km</string>
    <string name="east_r08_start_end">Anyksciai - Rokiskis</string>
    <string name="east_r08_difficulty">3</string>
    <string name="east_r08_full_description"><b>The route:</b> You will be riding from small town to small town. Some of them a really cozy, others at least will offer you groceries and a pint or two. Somehow it is a popular belief that this region is not the rich in sights. The route will make you question this.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> Anyksciai town. Notigale moor, well still more a scenic lake than a moor. Salos - a village in an island of a lake - a rarity in this region. Rokiskis town and manor.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b> Anyksciai can be reached by bus from major towns around - Vilnius, Kaunas, Panevezys. Rokiskis is on a railway, however, passenger services tend to be on weekends only. Alternatively, a bus to a major town should be available.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 3.  Around 70\u0025 of the route is paved, remaining 30\u0025 - gravel. Some gravel sections really test your tolerance for potholes.</string>


    <!-- Routes in South:-->
    <string name="south_r01_name">Search For the Old Railway</string>
    <string name="south_r01_distance">83 km</string>
    <string name="south_r01_start_end">Varena - Alytus</string>
    <string name="south_r01_difficulty">2</string>
    <string name="south_r01_full_description"><b>The route:</b> The line of this route on a map certainly does not look straight. Yes, it is not meant for logistics, but rather for the enjoyment of cycling. The roads you shall be going on will not be straight predictable lines as well. Numerous bends, ups and downs through gently rolling terrain of southern Lithuania will not allow for boredom.\n\nStart and end sections follow the tracks of an old railway, which was here at the beginning of the last century. Look around and try to spot old bridges and spillways, or previous stations, that are now turned into residential houses and orchards. In short - an interesting and sporty route.\n\nYou will see that the itinerary is divided into two disconnected parts. In the actual setting these parts are connected by a forest path and a pedestrian bridge over Varene river. The path stays on the south-west side of the lake. It may take a few attempts to find it hidden in bushes, but this is doable.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b>  Relics of an old railway. Many beautiful lakes. Punia hillfort. Nemunas river valley and a rather impressive pedestrian bridge over it.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Easy access by train to Varena. From Alytus it will not be difficult to catch a bus going to Vilnius, Druskininkai, or Kaunas. The Kaunas option, though is more assured.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 2.  Around 40\u0025 of the route is paved, the remaining 60\u0025 - gravel.</string>

    <string name="south_r02_name">More Lakes Than You Can Handle</string>
    <string name="south_r02_distance">71 km</string>
    <string name="south_r02_start_end">Rudiskes - Vievis</string>
    <string name="south_r02_difficulty">3</string>
    <string name="south_r02_full_description"><b>The route:</b> The route crosses highlands of southern Lithuania almost through the middle. Note, that highlands here is by Lithuanian standard. However, there will be a multitude of small hills and beautiful lakes, among which Vilkoksnis, Verniejus and Nava are especially picturesque. A strain for your muscles, but a really pleasant day trip for you.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b>  Dzukija lake district and highlands. "Dewil's hollow". A very pleasant small town of Aukstadvaris.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Easy access by train to both start and end.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 3.  Around 60\u0025 of the route is paved. Remaining 40\u0025 - gravel, some sections in forests will be sandy.</string>

    <string name="south_r03_name">The Curvy One - Part 1</string>
    <string name="south_r03_distance">136 km</string>
    <string name="south_r03_start_end">Kaunas - Alytus</string>
    <string name="south_r03_difficulty">2</string>
    <string name="south_r03_full_description"><b>The route:</b> Yes, the route is long. But this length is needed to get the full impression of Nemunas river. One would make a mistake deciding to shortcut one of the meanders along the way, for each curve opens you scenic sights one after the other.\n\nThere are a few places,  like Punia forest, where you will feel almost as if you were in a remote island. There are no alternate routes to reach those places, there are no bridges around. That is what keeps a lot of visitors away. Just count the meanders and forget the kilometers.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> A very peaceful and picturesque Nemunas river valley. Forests, river meanders and outcrops all through the route. Pazaislis monastery. Juniper valley. Old forest of Punia. Cozy villages and homesteads along the way.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Kaunas has very good access by both rail and bus. From Alytus it will not be difficult to catch a bus going to Vilnius, Druskininkai, or Kaunas.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 2.  Roughly around 80\u0025 of the route is paved, 20\u0025 - gravel.</string>

    <string name="south_r04_name">The Curvy One - Part 2</string>
    <string name="south_r04_distance">83 km</string>
    <string name="south_r04_start_end">Alytus - Druskininkai</string>
    <string name="south_r04_difficulty">3</string>
    <string name="south_r04_full_description"><b>The route:</b> The second part of the route is as scenic as the first one, but wilder. If you seek nature that is as undisturbed as it can be in the 21st century - it is here. For the full enjoyment travel without rush and try out each lake and creek.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> A very peaceful and picturesque Nemunas river valley. Forests, river meanders, cozy villages and homesteads along the way. Small town of Merkine. Liskiava monastery and hillforts. Druskininkai resort.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Alytus can be reached by bus from Vilnius, Druskininkai, or Kaunas. Druskininkai has really good bus connections with Vilnius and Kaunas.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 3.  Roughly around 70\u0025 of the route is gravel, 30\u0025 - paved. Quite a few sections in forests will be really sandy.</string>

    <string name="south_r05_name">Got Sand?</string>
    <string name="south_r05_distance">72 km</string>
    <string name="south_r05_start_end">Druskininkai - Varena</string>
    <string name="south_r05_difficulty">3</string>
    <string name="south_r05_full_description"><b>The route:</b> Oh don\'t be fooled by the first sections of this route which will  pass on even tarmac. Eventually you will enter a reign of sand and inland dunes. It may be difficult to recognize the dunes at first, as they are covered with forests, but you will certainly encounter sand. Unless your bicycle tires are on the wide side, this will be a good workout.\n\nHopefully, the first paragraph did not scare you off, as this route is definitely worthy a try. Extensive pine forests make it green and wild. Probably there will be only a few cars and travelers on the way, but a lot of nature and fresh air for your lungs.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> Druskininkai resort. Small, wild midforest lakes, fountains and streams. Ula river and Zackagiris trails. Zervynos ethnographic village.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Druskininkai has really good bus connections with Vilnius and Kaunas. Varena has a good railway connection with Vilnius.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 3.  Roughly around 80\u0025 of the route is gravel and sandy forest road, 20\u0025 - paved.</string>

    <string name="south_r06_name">Southern Rivers</string>
    <string name="south_r06_distance">48 km</string>
    <string name="south_r06_start_end">Varena - Merkine</string>
    <string name="south_r06_difficulty">2</string>
    <string name="south_r06_full_description"><b>The route:</b> Southern rivers - chilly water. This contradiction holds true for this route. Most of the rivers and streams here a fed by underground streams which keep you shiver even in the height of summer. Don\'t believe it - try Skroblus stream for instance. But the water is pure as inhabitants are scarce in this part of the country. Therefore, you can fully immerse into nature. Forest roads and pleasant nature from the start to the end.\n\nFor the final section, right after the highway bridge over Merkys river, you can choose an alternate route. Just turn left and follow a road that looks more like a track. It is harder, but much more scenic.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b>  Numerous smaller and larger rivers running near by. Remote, pleasant villages along the way.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Varena has a good railway connection with Vilnius. From Merkine it is not difficult to hop on a bus going to Vilnius. Pay attention, the bus stop is outside the town.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 2.  Around 60\u0025 of the route is gravel, 40\u0025 - paved.</string>

    <string name="south_r07_name">Places You Would Not Point On a Map</string>
    <string name="south_r07_distance">115 km</string>
    <string name="south_r07_start_end">Alytus - Druskininkai</string>
    <string name="south_r07_difficulty">2</string>
    <string name="south_r07_full_description"><b>The route:</b> Winding hilly roads of southern Lithuania - a pleasure for your eyes. A multitude of clear lakes and gentle hills among which stretches a chain of small cozy towns. Most of us probably know their names, but would hardly point their place on a map. For the majority this is a remote less traveled region. Well, maybe not for long, as the scenery is worthy.\n\nDepending on a season definitely stop at Zuvintas reserve. This is a place beloved by migrating birds. Just be prepared to adjust to their daily schedule, for the birds like early mornings and prime evening television time.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> Zuvintas reserve - a birdwathcing hotspot. Cozy small towns of southern Lithuania: Simnas, Seirijai, Veisiejai, Leipalingis. Veisiejai regional park with a multitude of lakes. Druskininkai resort.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Alytus can be reached by bus from Vilnius, Druskininkai, or Kaunas. Druskininkai has really good bus connections with Vilnius and Kaunas.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 2.  Roughly around 80\u0025 of the route is paved, the remaining 20\u0025 - gravel.</string>

    <string name="south_r08_name">Suddenly You Find a Highland</string>
    <string name="south_r08_distance">101 km</string>
    <string name="south_r08_start_end">Marijampole - Kybartai</string>
    <string name="south_r08_difficulty">3</string>
    <string name="south_r08_full_description"><b>The route:</b> You start in plain fields of southwest, you end up in plain fields of southwest. But would you suspect to find a marvelous hilly region in between? Just some 30 kilometers away from the start,  Kalvarija - the name of a small town, gives you a small hint. The name partially means - "a hilly place". And afterwards they start and roll more and more with each kilometer. By the way, en route awaits a real treat - Vistytis regional park.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> Interesting small towns on route. Vistytis regional park. A perfectly scenic lake of Vistytis.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Both Marijampole and Kybartai have good railway connections with Kaunas.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 3.  Around 70\u0025 of the route is gravel, the remaining 30\u0025 - paved. Those hills in the middle will take their share.</string>


    <!-- Routes in West:-->
    <string name="west_r01_name">Along Nemunas to Sunset - Part 1</string>
    <string name="west_r01_distance">91 km</string>
    <string name="west_r01_start_end">Kaunas - Jurbarkas</string>
    <string name="west_r01_difficulty">1</string>
    <string name="west_r01_full_description"><b>The route:</b> Routes along river valleys always are special in a way. Sights that you find traveling along the bottom of valleys are sometimes very different from those that you find climbing on top just a kilometer or so away. This part of Nemunas river abides to this rule. Furthermore, it will be hard to find a more picturesque route with such abundance of castles, manors, hillforts and cozy small towns. Take your time and visit all the sites along the route.\n\nThe last part of the route between Skirsnemune and Jurbarkas can and should be traveled along the river as well. There is a good cycling route that is not shown on the main map.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> Old part of Kaunas. A very peaceful and picturesque Nemunas river valley. Cozy villages and small towns of Kacergine, Zapyskis, Vilkija, Seredzius, etc ... , almost each one along the route. Zapyskis gothic church. Vilkija ferry. Castles, manors and hillforts along the route.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Kaunas has very good access by both rail and bus. From Jurbarkas it is fairly easy to catch a bus back to Kaunas or further west to Klaipeda.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 1.  Mostly paved and even. Apart from Kaunas town, without much traffic.</string>

    <string name="west_r02_name">Along Nemunas to Sunrise</string>
    <string name="west_r02_distance">119 km</string>
    <string name="west_r02_start_end">Jurbarkas - Kaunas</string>
    <string name="west_r02_difficulty">2</string>
    <string name="west_r02_full_description"><b>The route:</b> One more atmospheric route along river valley, a close cousin to another route: Along Nemunas to Sunset - Part 1. Though it is a bit more strenuous and a bit less impressive. Still all the way from the start to the end you will have a beautiful river on your side. The sights will be especially  lovely during early to mid fall. Apart from nature there are quite a few hillforts and manors, a fun ferry crossing and a well worth Kaunas old town.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> A very peaceful and picturesque Nemunas river valley. Cozy villages and small towns of Gelgaudiskis, Vilkija, Kulautuva and others. Sudargas hillforts complex. Vaiguva stream. Vilkija ferry. Manors and hillforts along the route. Old part of Kaunas.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Jurbarkas has rather good bus service connecting it to Kaunas or Klaipeda. Kaunas has very good access by both rail and bus.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 2.  Roughly around 50\u0025 of the route is paved, 50\u0025 - gravel. Some sections along the river will be just a track running through meadows.</string>

    <string name="west_r03_name">Along Nemunas to Sunset - Part 2</string>
    <string name="west_r03_distance">123 km</string>
    <string name="west_r03_start_end">Jurbarkas - Rusne</string>
    <string name="west_r03_difficulty">1</string>
    <string name="west_r03_full_description"><b>The route:</b> This section along Nemunas is particularly interesting for its German heritage, major part of it has been a part of this country for more than half of milenium. Each village and town along the way has at least a light touch of german architecture.\n\nApart from architecture it will be really interesting to visit and see: Bitenai stork colony (April - July), srping flood area (March - May), Rambynas pagan sanctuary and many other interesting places along the way.\n\nAt times you will be very close to the border with Russia, thus take your time and binoculars to peek into this neighbouring country. The travel ends with Rusne island - a perfect place for every birdwatcher.\n\nThe second part of the route between Pagegiai and Silute could be travelled along small gravel roads much closer to Nemunas river. If you have time and stamina - this is an option well worth to consider.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> A very peaceful and picturesque Nemunas river valley. Cozy villages and small towns of Smalininkai, Viesvile, Vilkyciai, Bitenai, etc ... , almost each one along the route. German heritage remains along all the way. Bitenai stork colony. Rambynas pagan sanctuary. Nemunas spring flood area.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Jurbarkas has rather good bus service connecting it to Kaunas or Klaipeda. From Rusne you will have 3 options: cycle arroud 10 km to Uostadvaris and catch a boat to Nida (although this service is very seasonal); cycle back to Silute and catch a bus to Klaipeda; lastly, you can continue your cycling trip  along the route: Stopped by the Sea Lagoon.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 1.  80\u0025 of the route is paved, remaining 20\u0025 - gravel. There are only a few hills allong the way.</string>

    <string name="west_r04_name">Stopped by the Sea Lagoon - Part 1</string>
    <string name="west_r04_distance">59 km</string>
    <string name="west_r04_start_end">Rusne - Vente</string>
    <string name="west_r04_difficulty">1</string>
    <string name="west_r04_full_description"><b>The route:</b> This route is completely flat and mostly forestless. Usually, these qualities would not seem to offer an interesting day out. However, the region you will be traveling through is really special. All the time you will be just a stone\'s throw away from a see lagoon and delta of a major river in the region.\n\nThe special maritime vibe is felt all the way. You will be met by flocks of birds, busy fishermen and maybe even some shy wild animals. This will be a perfect trip for those who like birdwhatching. Also, if you are early in season, you can be lucky to observe spring flood of Nemunas.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> Picturesque Nemunas river delta. Cozy villages and small towns along the route. German heritage remains along all the way. Nemunas spring flood area. Birdwathching.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Rusne is 8 kilometers away from Silute. There are rather good bus connections between Silute and Kaunas or Klaipeda. The end point in Vente village is more "problematic" with transport. You will have either:  to catch a boat to Nida (this service is very seasonal), or to continue your cycling trip  along the second part of this route. Actually, both options are perfect.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 1.  70\u0025 of the route is paved, remaining 30\u0025 - gravel. Every kilometer is flat and easy.</string>

    <string name="west_r05_name">Stopped by the Sea Lagoon - Part 2</string>
    <string name="west_r05_distance">97 km</string>
    <string name="west_r05_start_end">Vente - Sventoji</string>
    <string name="west_r05_difficulty">1</string>
    <string name="west_r05_full_description"><b>The route:</b> Strangely, even if you have just one day to spare, a special holiday feeling will lead you all the way on this route; as if it was a vacation. A sea lagoon or the sea itself will be near by all the time. There will be lots of water, forests and dunes.\n\nSome urban exploration - Klaipeda\'s old town - should be on your list as well. There are good chances that you will like to stay longer on this route.\n\nUnfortunately, there are only a few designated campsites. However, "cowboy camping", though not strictly legal, is always an option. It comes with some requirements - leave no trace, do not advertise too much and avoid nature reserves.\n\nBetween Deverna and Klaipeda there is a more scenic and direct route that follows King Vilhelm\'s channel. But its sandy conditions will require your energy. It starts 1 kilometer past Dreverna, right after the bridge over the channel.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> Cozy villages of Vente, Kintai, Dreverna. Many german heritage remains. Birdwathching and kitesurfing. Klaipeda\'s old town. Seashore trail. Lots of options for dipping yourself in the sea. Natural seashore dunes in Sventoji.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  The starting point in Vente village is a bit "problematic" with transport. You will have either:  to catch a boat from Nida (this service is very seasonal), or bike here along the first part of this route from Silute. There are rather good bus connections between Silute and Kaunas or Klaipeda. Sventoji has rather good bus connections with Klaipeda, Kaunas and Vilnius.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 1.  90\u0025 of the route is paved, remaining 10\u0025 - gravel. An alternative, more direct and scenic section between Dreverna and Klaipeda is rather tough due to its sandy conditions.</string>

    <string name="west_r06_name">The Furthest West You Can Get</string>
    <string name="west_r06_distance">59 km</string>
    <string name="west_r06_start_end">Klaipeda - Nida</string>
    <string name="west_r06_difficulty">1</string>
    <string name="west_r06_full_description"><b>The route:</b> Probably the most known and popular biking route in the country. This probably tells enough. Simply marvelous and scenic. Most cyclists, however, after the short ferry trip from Klaipeda, rarely venture a few kilometers north to the northern end of the Curonian Spit. Refrain from this mistake and make this worthy detour.\n\nIf you are not short of time, you will really want to spend more than one day here. Unfortunately, if you are a fan of camping, there are just a few designated campsites, which get crowded during peak season. However, "cowboy camping", though not strictly legal, is always an option. It comes with some requirements - leave no trace, do not advertise too much and avoid nature reserves.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> Each settlement along the way is marvelous. Klaipeda\'s old town. Southern breakwater of Klaipeda\'s seaport. Seashore sauna in Smiltyne. Lots of options for dipping yourself in the sea. Great sand dunes of the Curonian Spit - especially the Grey dunes and Parnidis dune.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Klaipeda has good connections with all major towns in Lithuania. From Nida you can: get on a bus back to Klaipeda (though this gets too crowded for cyclists during peak season); catch a ferry to Klaipeda (if you are short of time, this is the recommended option during peak season); get on a boat and cross the lagoon to Vente village - cycling routes there are really worth your time.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 1.  Almost all the route is paved. If you make at least a few breaks to enjoy the sea or lagoon, you will not even notice how you reach the end point.</string>

    <string name="west_r07_name">The Big Small River Valley</string>
    <string name="west_r07_distance">85 km</string>
    <string name="west_r07_start_end">Jurbarkas - Silale</string>
    <string name="west_r07_difficulty">3</string>
    <string name="west_r07_full_description"><b>The route:</b> This route can be divided into two parts: the first part - Karsuva wood will be a quite travel under the shade of trees; the second - Pagramatis regional park - a place still rarely visited, however, full of natural beauty. Travel through the park will be a prize for you - a fair exchange for the energy lost.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> Smalininkai a cozy little town right on the border, full of german heritage. Marvelous nature of Pagramatis regional park. Akmena river valley.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Jurbarkas and Silale both have rather good bus service connecting it to Kaunas or Klaipeda.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 3.  Roughly around 60\u0025 of the route is gravel, 40\u0025 - paved. Some sections in forests are sandy.</string>

    <string name="west_r08_name">The Wild, the Odd and the Beautiful</string>
    <string name="west_r08_distance">117 km</string>
    <string name="west_r08_start_end">Plunge - Sventoji</string>
    <string name="west_r08_difficulty">2</string>
    <string name="west_r08_full_description"><b>The route:</b> If you want to see a lot of different places, travel through some wild and remote regions and finally reward yourself with a sea - this is the way. Some of the sights will seem a bit odd - like Orvidai museum, full of bizarre stone sculptures, or cold war museum. Other views will be really wild - such as Dunika bog. The route will prove its name.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> Cozy villages and small towns on the way: Plunge, Berzoras, Plateliai, Salantai ... (the list is longer). Oginsikis palace with a surrounding park. Cold war museum. Samogitia national park. Orvidai museum. Juniper forest near Salantai. Dunika bog trail. Natural seashore dunes in Sventoji.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Easy access by train to Plunge. Sventoji has rather good bus connections with Klaipeda, Kaunas and Vilnius.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 2.  70\u0025 of the route is paved, remaining 30\u0025 - gravel.</string>


    <!-- Routes in North:-->
    <string name="north_r01_name">Following Dubysa River</string>
    <string name="north_r01_distance">111 km</string>
    <string name="north_r01_start_end">Siauliai - Raseiniai</string>
    <string name="north_r01_difficulty">2</string>
    <string name="north_r01_full_description"><b>The route:</b> Dubysa river currently is a destination only for water activities enthusiasts, but the routes along its valley are really worth your cycle wheels. The first 10 - 20 kilometers of the route may seem a bit dull, but this changes 180 degrees once you get closer to the river.\n\nRoutes along river valleys always are special in a way: hilly horizon, river meanders, small farmsteads scattered along the way - to name a few. Dubysa river has a reputation to be one of the most scenic. If you have time, it is really worth to explore a few additional minor roads that run in parallel to the river or get on top of hillforts nearby.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> Dubysa river - perfect for camping or water attractions. Tyuvenai regional park. Lyduvenai railway bridge; currently there is no access on top of the bridge, but this may change in near future.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Starting point in Siauliai is at the railway station - there are good connections with other major towns. From Raseiniai it should be rather easy to catch a bus to Kaunas, Klaipeda, Vilnius or Siauliai.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 2.  70\u0025 of the distance is paved, remaining 30\u0025 - gravel, some of it bad.</string>

    <string name="north_r02_name">In Search for Moon Landscape</string>
    <string name="north_r02_distance">106 km</string>
    <string name="north_r02_start_end">Siauliai - Papile</string>
    <string name="north_r02_difficulty">2</string>
    <string name="north_r02_full_description"><b>The route:</b> This route shall take you to Menciai quarry - an interesting and bizarre place with a canyon like landscape. It is not a real mountain canyon by any measure, but your photocamera will really have some work to do. There will be quite a lot of rural landscapes on the way. If you are not a fan of those - then Venta river valley will await at the last section. The water is clean and you can find a few wild campsites near by.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> Menciai quarry. Venta river valley. Small pleasant towns on the way.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Siauliai has good connections by both railway and bus. Although, starting from Kursenai may be better in case you would like to have a shorter ride. There is a railway station quite close to this town. Endpoint in Papile is also served by a railway.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 2.  80\u0025 of the route is paved, remaining 20\u0025 - gravel, some with annoying potholes.</string>

    <string name="north_r03_name">A Slice of Western Aukstaitija</string>
    <string name="north_r03_distance">83 km</string>
    <string name="north_r03_start_end">Panevezys - Kedainiai</string>
    <string name="north_r03_difficulty">1</string>
    <string name="north_r03_full_description"><b>The route:</b> This route offers a lot of interesting historic and cultural sights in its rather short distance. Nevezis river valley - a place of surprisingly pleasant nature sights amidst the region of central flats that is busy with farming. You will be seeing this river quite often along the way. Krekenava regional park also has pleasant natural sights. Traveling along this route will really change your initial attitude about this region.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> Upyte village - which in medieval times was an significant town and a place of an important castle of Grad Duchy of Lithuania. Nevezis river valley. Krekenava regional park. A herd of bisons - unfortunately not completely wild. Seteiniai manor - an interesting place where once Nobel prize laureate Oscar Milosz was born and lived and which is very related to his works. Kedainiai old town.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Panevezys can be easily reached by bus and, though not so easy, by train. There are good railway connections from Kedainiai.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 1.  The route is mostly paved and fairly even.</string>

    <string name="north_r04_name">Through Levuo Valley</string>
    <string name="north_r04_distance">55 km</string>
    <string name="north_r04_start_end">Panevezys - Kupiskis</string>
    <string name="north_r04_difficulty">2</string>
    <string name="north_r04_full_description"><b>The route:</b> There is a popular belief that this region can not compete with others in terms of its sights. However, one could bet that quite a few Lithuanians do not even know where is the location of Levuo river. Thus, you really will not meet any bicycle tourist here. Therefore, you will be able to keep all the beautiful sights of this river valley only to yourself.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b>  Levuo river valley. A few of manor houses along the way.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Access by train to both start and end. Though train service may only be weekends. However, Panevezys can be easily reached by bus.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 2.  The route is almost evenly shared between gravel and pavement.</string>

    <string name="north_r05_name">Straight to the North</string>
    <string name="north_r05_distance">113 km</string>
    <string name="north_r05_start_end">Kupiskis - Birzai</string>
    <string name="north_r05_difficulty">2</string>
    <string name="north_r05_full_description"><b>The route:</b> Simple rural landscapes can look really good, just pick suitable weather. However, this route is much more than fields and country homes. A border between Latvia and Lithuania running along a beautiful river. The famous sinkhole region near Birzai. Rocky outcrops - a rarity in this country. There is lots to see, therefore take a tent and have this route in two days.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b>  Nemunelio Radviliskis and Skaistkalne (in Latvia) - small cozy towns right on the border. Rocky outcrops of Nemunelis river. Numerous Sinkholes near Birzai. Birzai castle and Astravas manor with a longest pedestrian bridge in Lithuania.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Kupiskis is accessed by train, although only on weekends. There are rather good bus connections from Birzai to Siauliai, Vilnius, Kaunas, Panevezys.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 2.  80\u0025 of the distance is paved, remaining 20\u0025 - gravel, some of it bad.</string>

    <string name="north_r06_name">Hilly Samogitia</string>
    <string name="north_r06_distance">71 km</string>
    <string name="north_r06_start_end">Telsiai - Plunge</string>
    <string name="north_r06_difficulty">3</string>
    <string name="north_r06_full_description"><b>The route:</b> A very picturesque route that combines both nature and towns, thought these towns are by no means places of hustle. Most of the villages along the way will take you back maybe even a hundred years, but in a good way of tradition. It is really worth to take a break and camp in Zemaitija national park. Also, Cold war museum is a place that should be high on the list.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> Very pleasant Telsiai and Plunge towns. Beautiful villages along the way: Zemaiciu Kalvarija, Berzoras, Plateliai. Oginsikis palace with a surrounding park. Cold war museum. A lot of lakes and forests for you to enjoy.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Easy access by train to both start and end.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 3.  60\u0025 of the route is gravel, remaining 40\u0025 - paved. Rolling hills will not let you doze.</string>

    <string name="north_r07_name">From Pagan to Present - Part 1</string>
    <string name="north_r07_distance">90 km</string>
    <string name="north_r07_start_end">Telsiai - Kraziai</string>
    <string name="north_r07_difficulty">3</string>
    <string name="north_r07_full_description"><b>The route:</b> Again one more picturesque route. This is a long but certainly not boring chain of old villages, and historic sites. This itinerary can be both - a good lesson of history, showing you sites dating back as far as millennium or so, and a way to enjoy nature and calm landscapes.\n\nYou will really get to know one of most important historic regions of Lithuania - Samogitia. If you have a good guide or dare yourself, definitely try out Sietuva "kulgrinda" - a hidden underwater stony road across a swamp.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> central part of Telsiai. Beautiful villages along the way: Tverai, Laukuva, Kaltinenai, Kraziai. Lopaiciai pagan sanctuary. Sietuva "kulgrinda". Hillforts and rolling hills along the way.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Easy access by train to Telsiai. End point in Kraziai has very limited options for transport. You will have two options: either to continue to the second part of the route, or to bike an additional 20 kilometers to Kryzkalnis, where bus service is rather good.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 3.  Roughly around 50\u0025 of the route is paved, 50\u0025 - gravel. Hilly and stony gravel will train you muscles.</string>

    <string name="north_r08_name">From Pagan to Present - Part 2</string>
    <string name="north_r08_distance">87 km</string>
    <string name="north_r08_start_end">Kraziai - Telsiai</string>
    <string name="north_r08_difficulty">3</string>
    <string name="north_r08_full_description"><b>The route:</b> Continuation of the first section of the route. Similar in beauty and sites, but a little bit less enigmatic - pagan time sites here are substituted with monasteries and manors. Satrija hillfort takes a special place in Lithuanian folklore. It is believed that this is the site where witches meet. If you spend a night nearby, maybe you will have luck or not and see any. However, you will definitely have an impressive 360 degrees of panorama.\n\n<b>Main sights:</b> Beautiful villages along the way: Kraziai, Varniai, Luoke. A number of hillforts and rolling hills along the way. Central part of Telsiai.\n\n<b>Getting in and away:</b>  Start point in Kraziai has very limited options for transport. If you are not continuing this route from the direction of Kaltinenai (see From Pagan to Present - Part 1), then you can reach Kraziai from Kryzkalnis - a village 20 kilometers to southeast, with good bus connections. From the end point - Telsiai - there is a good railway service.\n\n<b>Difficulty level:</b> 3.  Roughly around 50\u0025 of the route is paved, 50\u0025 - gravel, some of which is hilly and stony.</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>

</resources>
